Justin M. Lugo

2616 White Oak Ln. Kannapolis, North Carolina 28083 **Phone**: (252) 503-1948

Email: jlug331221@gmail.com

Website: https://jlug331221.github.io/personal-website/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-lugo/

Career Summary

Computer scientist/software engineer and Marine Corps veteran with 2+ years of professional software development experience. Huge passion for developing amazing applications. Always eager and open to new challenges that will help me grow as a developer. Previous positions include working within Formula 1 and the United States Air Force. Education includes a Bachelor's degree and Master's degree in Computer Science.

Education and Training

August 2016 - May 2018
 Texas Tech University

M.Sc. in Computer Science, GPA: 4.0 on a 4.0 Scale

SMART Scholarship Recipient

August 2013 - May 2016
 East Carolina University

B.Sc. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.81 on a 4.0 Scale

Relevant Courses:

Advanced Data Structures

Analysis of Algorithms

Programming Languages

Advanced Operating Systems

Database Management

Computer Architecture

Software Engineering

A.I. - Intelligent Agents, Knowledge

Software Project Management Representation and Reasoning

Logic for Computer Scientists Theory and Practice of Logic Programming

June 2009 - June 2013
 United States Marine Corps

Military Occupational Specialty: 0651 - Data Cyber Network Specialist Specialized Training: Cisco Networking, VMWare, NetApp Filers, Microsoft Server 2003/2008, Microsoft Windows XP | 7 and multiple Linux environments

Experience and Technical Skills

Languages	Java, C/C++, PHP, Python, BASH scripting, C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
	Prolog, and Answer, Set Programming (Clingo and SPARC)
Source Control	Git with/without DevOps integration
Web Frameworks	Laravel and ASP.NET
Operating Systems	Linux, Windows, Mac
Database Systems	MySQL and NoSQL
CFD	ParaView post processing automation with Python. STAR-CCM+
	automation with Java.

Professional Accomplishments

Haas F1 Team | June 2019 to Present | Software Engineer

- Maintain the Python codebase for ParaView post-processing of the CFD simulation results
- Setup and configure version control (Git) with Azure DevOps for all software development source code
- Develop and maintain a timekeeping application with Laravel/VueJS
- Performed MSSQL database setup and configuration.
- Assist with the setup and current maintenance of a Laravel CFD web application.

Tinker Air Force Base | June 2018 to June 2019 | Computer Scientist

- Maintained software for the suite of applications within the E3 AWACS aircraft
- Worked within a Scrum team and in an Agile development setting
- Responsibilities were to resolve software faults and improve legacy code
- Relevant languages: C++, Java, and shell scripting

Texas Tech University, College of Media and Communications | September 2016 to July 2017 | Web Developer

- Managed the College of Media and Communications website
- Made updates to the site and creating new site content

Employment History

• June 2019 – Present

Software Engineer - Haas F1 Team, Kannapolis, NC

June 2018 - June 2019

Computer Scientist - Tinker Air Force Base, Oklahoma City, OK

• July 2017 - May 2018

Full Time Graduate Student with the SMART Scholarship - Texas Tech University

September 2016 - July 2017

Web Developer - Texas Tech University, College of Media and Communications Lubbock, TX

• July 2016 - August 2016

Teaching Assistant - Austin Coding Academy

San Antonio, TX

• June 2016 - August 2016

Lead Instructor | Teaching Assistant - Youth Code Jam San Antonio

San Antonio, TX

• September 2015 - April 2016

Biology Tutor | IT Lab Administrator - East Carolina University, Athletic Student Development Greenville, NC

October 2013 - August 2015

Student Laboratory IT Technician - East Carolina University, IT Computing Services Greenville, NC

• June 2009 - June 2013

Data Cyber Network Specialist - U.S Marine Corps

Jacksonville, NC